## **DENIS COUTO**

Senior Systems Engineer

+353 083 151 4346
Brazilian
denis.couto@gmail.com
linkedin.com/in/deniscouto/ | about.me/docouto







Infrastructure and automation engineer with +18 years of progressive experience in infrastructure mostly focused on Microsoft stack both on-prem and cloud.

Supporting, maintaining, and optimizing small to large environments using all sorts of solutions stacks from Microsoft, VMware, Citrix, HPE and others. PowerShell heavy user able to make use of advanced features of the language.

## **Skills & Expertise**

- Extensive knowledge of Microsoft Stack (onprem and Azure).
- Solid knowledge of PowerShell.
- Working knowledge in configuration/automation tools such as Bicep, Ansible and Terraform.
- Working knowledge of Linux administration (CentOS/Ubuntu).
- Good understanding of CI/CD, containers, orchestration tools such as Azure DevOps, Octopus Deploy, Docker and Kubernetes.

### **Certifications**

Azure: DevOps Expert

Azure: Administrator Associate

CC-VAD-CC: Citrix CVAD Service on Citrix

MCSE: Cloud Platform and Infrastructure Cloud

## **Professional Experience**

## Citrix Systems, Dublin, Ireland Senior Escalation Engineer

2018 - Present

Working in the EMEA Escalation team, I provide analysis of complex problems in a 24x7 follow the sun support environment.

In-Depth knowledge of *Citrix DaaS* and Citrix Cloud, leverage debugging techniques to manage high severity cases which can be politically or technically challenging daily.

Day to day goes through SysInternals tools, PowerShell, Splunk, Azure, code review on Sourcegraph and Bitbucket, memory dump analysis with WinDBG, trace analysis with Baregrep, engaging Engineering for further troubleshooting through Jira.

I delivered some training sessions to Frontline engineers on how to leverage PowerShell console during troubleshooting sessions with customers to act quickly and effectively while assessing the customer issue.

#Citrix #DaaS #Azure #Engineering #Debugging #Splunk

# Ergo Group, Dublin, Ireland

2015 - 2018

Level 3 Support Engineer

Working on escalation and on BAU tasks for several customers (Aercap, CIE, Goshawk, AerLingus, Dunbia and many others) managing a variety of products and services, such as: Windows Server (2008 to 2016), Linux (Ubuntu, CentOS), Azure, Office 365, Hyper-V, VMware ESXi, Netscaler, Xenapp, MS RDS, Exchange, System Center and others.

Also worked on a dedicated team for a single customer where beyond the daily operational tasks I had the opportunity to automate a series of tasks through PowerShell using functions and modules that helped to:

• Finding details of servers combining data from AD, Solarwinds and VMware.

- Finding and gather details of SQL Server databases an SQL Server instances.
- Syncing employee's photos in Active Directory for later use in Skype and other platforms.
- Wrapping APIs to better integration between LOB applications.
- Backing up, encrypting SQL Databases and securely sharing with 3<sup>rd</sup> party vendor.

For this same customer I was responsible for their continuous deploy environment based on *Octopus Deploy*, orchestrating with a 3<sup>rd</sup> party vendor the deployment of their main application throughout Test/UAT/PROD environments and making sure those environments were in sync regarding their data.

I was also engaged on the planning phase to bring their custom intranet web site to Gitlab and enable their 3<sup>rd</sup> party vendor to be able to commit code and get it pushed to the appropriate environments, instead of doing screen sharing to deploy updates.

#Level3 #Virtualization #Azure #Automation #Octopus

# DoMore! Soluções em Produtividade, São Paulo, Brazil

2009 - 2015

Senior Microsoft Infrastructure Engineer

- Planning, deploying, and managing medium to large SharePoint farms and applications for companies like Odebrecht, Vale, PWC, Pfizer, Carrefour and others.
- Administering internal and cloud infrastructure running several Microsoft solutions such as Hyper-V,
   AD, WSUS, IIS, SharePoint (2007,2010, 2013), Office 365, SQL Server, Visual Studio Team Services.
- Automating SharePoint Installation and web sites deployment trough PowerShell.

#SharePoint #Powershell #Deployment

#### Atento Brasil, São Paulo, Brazil

2006 - 2008

L3 Server Support Engineer

- Performing 3<sup>rd</sup> level support to Windows environment with more than 10.000 users and 12 locations nationwide.
- Managing VMware ESXi and Microsoft network products (AD, DNS, DHCP, WSUS), Exchange Server 2007 cluster with BlackBerry Integration Services.
- Performing changes on environment through change requests and working on support tickets.

#Level3 #Windows

### SSI Consultoria, São Paulo, Brazil

2004 - 2006

Server Administrator

- Managing a Windows network environment including Active Directory, DNS, DHCP, RRAS and File Services.
- Administering SQL Server together with Visual Source Safe.
- Managing Linux (Red Hat) Iptables Firewall, Web Proxy with Squid and reports with SARG.

#SysAdmin #Firewall #Proxy #SCM

# **Education & Trainings**

- Degree in Computer Networking Faculdade Eniac (São Paulo Brazil)
- VMware V6 Fast Track SureSkills (Ireland)
- Skype for Business Partner Technical Airlift *Microsoft* (Ireland)
- Implementing Microsoft Azure Infrastructure Solutions Global Knowledge (Ireland)